### Contact

400 S OHIO AVE #1099 LIVE OAK, FL 32064 3862499739 (Mobile) trevor.d.reid@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/treid (LinkedIn) github.com/tdreid (Portfolio) tdreid.github.io/ (Personal) busy.org/@tdre (Blog)

## Top Skills

JavaScript PHP WordPress

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Characteristics of a Great Scrum Master

# Trevor Reid, MBA

Developer | Blockchain and Data Science Enthusiast Buffalo/Niagara, New York Area

## Summary

Experienced Software Developer & MBA – Full Stack experience using Node.js, C#, Python, SQL, GraphQL and other languages. Background includes front end as well as API's; greenfield and legacy projects. As an entrepreneurial minded team player I provide broad expertise to further a well rounded understanding of problem domains. From Coding to Marketing, Management, Managerial Economics, Intellectual Property Law and beyond. I have years of Back End, Front End and Blockchain Development experience and focus on delivering highest value with agility and elegance.

# Experience

Boston Valley Terra Cotta Full Stack Developer March 2019 - Present

BuildTeam - Blockchain Innovators Full Stack Developer February 2019 - Present

Upwork
Software Developer
June 2011 - Present
Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Varied shorter term contracts in web design and development. I took on quite a bit of PHP work including Magento, WordPress and Laravel.

OPIE Software
Developer
February 2017 - March 2019 (2 years 2 months)
Gainesville, Florida Area

Full stack developer using C#, JavaScript (React) and Node.js to author sector leading healthcare practice management software and mobile application.

Eagle (G.E.T.) Manufacturing Limited Software Developer May 2012 - August 2013 (1 year 4 months) Hialeah, FL

Authored manufacturing management and reporting software to coordinate activities of more than 500 expertly trained employees across diverse construction disciplines ranging from the workings of a cast iron foundry and industrial fabrication to metallurgical processing and robotic controlled materials formulation.

#### **UBC**

Senior Software Developer September 2008 - March 2011 (2 years 7 months) Bethesda, MD

Created clinical study management software with an emphasis on drug safety, data integrity, and federal compliance. Used SQL and SharePoint to create reports and dashboards.

National Endowment for Democracy
Web & Database Developer
April 2007 - August 2008 (1 year 5 months)

As technical adviser to a cross-functional team successfully built consensus leading to selection, design, and implementation of web based dashboard that will streamline financial and program management of grant portfolios, meeting industry best practice in this area.

Handled multiple projects using SQL, VB.NET, C#, Java, and SharePoint while meeting all deadlines.

Wrote exposition on issues pertaining to technical, security and policy considerations.

Interviewed colleagues, evaluated projects and briefed managers on proposal outcomes.

Northrop Grumman Software Developer June 2006 - November 2006 (6 months)

As contractor computer programmer contributed Java, SQL, and Visual Basic code to complex, multi-faceted government benefits tracking system.

Authored and reviewed detailed design requirements, functional, technical, and test specifications in prose and UML.

Conducted rigorous quality assurance reviews.

Johns Hopkins Medicine Senior Developer July 2001 - May 2006 (4 years 11 months) Baltimore, Maryland

Authored patient management software with an emphasis on safety, security, HIPAA compliance and improving quality of life for all. Integrated diverse API's including desktop, kiosk, legacy mainframe and emerging mobile technologies.

First Data Merchant Services

Programmer Analyst III
October 1999 - July 2001 (1 year 10 months)

Developed software for secure access to financial data for use by banks and credit card processors.

Ingram Micro

Analyst

April 1997 - October 1999 (2 years 7 months)

Created database and spreadsheet solution for account reconciliation and document management.

## Education

The Johns Hopkins University - Paul H. Nitze School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS)

Graduate Coursework, International Studies · (2006 - 2006)

American Military University

Master of Business Administration, Cross-cultural Management · (2009 - 2011)

**Excelsior College** 

Bachelor of Science, Liberal Arts · (2002 - 2006)